mediacom.com 2019-05-03

# Privacy Policy | MediaCom Worldwide

How and why we collect data and covering your choices.

(last update, 24.05.18)

 ** _WHO ARE WE?_**

MediaCom Holdings Limited (“ **MediaCom** ”), is a global media planning and buying agency and is a part of GroupM Worldwide, LLC, which is the umbrella for a network group of media planning and buying and related media and technology companies. MediaCom Holdings Limited is the legal entity responsible for the data that MediaCom collects.

This notice outlines how and why MediaCom collects and uses personal data specifically from visits to the MediaCom websites (“ **Websites** ”): <http://www.mediacom.com/> and any related or affiliated sites, such as <http://mediacombeyondadvertising.com/>, <http://sportandentertainment.mediacom.com/> and <http://www.mediacom-careers.com/> or country-level sites such as [www.mediacom.com/uk](http://www.mediacom.com/uk).

This notice also explains your rights as someone who may provide personal data to MediaCom through the Websites and how to exercise these rights. If you are an individual residing in the EEA or Switzerland you should be aware that our DPO can contacted at [DPO@GroupM.com](mailto:DPO@GroupM.com).

We respect the privacy of users of our website and recognise that when you choose to provide us with information about yourself, you trust us to act in a responsible manner with that information. This privacy policy contains important information about how we use your personal data, it is important that you read this privacy notice together with any other privacy notice or fair processing notice we may provide on specific occasions when we are collecting or processing personal data about you to ensure you are fully aware of how and why we are using your data. This privacy notice supplements the other notices and is not intended to override them.

 ** _WHAT INFORMATION IS COLLECTED AND USED BY MEDIACOM?_**

We collect information that enables us to identify your browser and device and tell us which pages within our Website you visit and on which pages you spend the most time. We do this by using the following:

 **Cookie:**

is a small alphanumeric text file that we automatically assign to visitors to our website. It is stored in your browser and allows us to identify your interaction with us.

Sometimes a cookie resides on your device for just the single time you’re visiting our Website; this is called a session cookie. Sometimes a cookie remains on your device until you delete it or it expires automatically; this is called a persistent cookie. Both types of cookies are used on our Websites.

IP **address:**

means Internet protocol address

 **Pixel:**

is a line of code that sits within our webpages and which we use to record that you have visited a particular page within our Websites.

If you don’t agree to us using cookies and the above information, you may prevent their use through your browser settings. By choosing not to accept cookies, certain Website features may not work as we have intended.e use some or all of this information to improve your website experience by delivering content that you are likely to prefer on future visits. Our lawful basis for this type of processing is that we have a legitimate interest in understanding and improving your experience of our Website.

 ** _Specific Cookie Types used by MediaCom_**

 **Cookie**  |  **Performance Analytics Tracking**  | This type of cookie provides aggregated information about where a user may go on the Website.  
---|---|---  
 **Google Analytics**       |  **Google Analytics (persistent)**       | MediaCom uses Google Analytics to help us analyse how visitors use the Websites. Among other things, Google Analytics uses cookies to collect information about the number of visits to the Website, the webpage that referred visitors to the Website, language, device, browser and operating system, the pages visitors view within the Website and other similar details. We do not share this information with third parties. When used this way the Google Analytics cookie is a persistent cookie, and will remain on your device until the cookie expires or you delete it. These cookies may appear as _utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz, _utmv, _utmt.  
|  **Google Analytics** **(session)**|  This cookie may appear as has_js. We do not retain this data as it is deleted upon closing of your browser, and therefore we cannot share it with any third parties.  
 **Click Dimensions**|  **Web Analytics**  | cuvid: This cookie is typically written to the browser upon the first visit to the site from that web browser. If the cookie has been deleted by the browser operator, and the browser subsequently visits the site, a new __cuid cookie is written with a different visitor unique ID. This cookie is used to determine unique visitors to the site and it is updated with each page view. Additionally, this cookie is provided with a unique ID that the application uses to ensure both the validity and accessibility of the cookie as an extra security measure. Expires 2 years after setup/update.cusid: This cookie is used to establish and continue a user session with the site. When a user views a page on the site, the script code attempts to update this cookie. If it does not find the cookie, a new one is written and a new session is established. Each time a user visits a different page on the site, this cookie is updated to expire in 30 minutes, thus continuing a single session for as long as user activity continues within 30-minute intervals. This cookie expires when a user pauses on a page on the site for longer than 30 minutes. Expires 30 minutes after set up/update.cuvon: Used to signal the last time a visitor viewed a page. Expires 30 minutes from set up/update.<http://help.clickdimensions.com/clickdimensions-cookies-for-web-analytics/>   
 **Cookie Preference**  | | This cookie is used to remember a user's choice about cookies on mediacom.com. Where users have previously indicated a preference, that user's preference will be stored in that cookie.  
 **Security Breach notification form cookie**    |   **Session cookie**      | This cookie is set by our content management system upon arriving on the mediacom.com website. It is used to identify a user's ASP.NET session (ASP.NET is a web application framework, originally developped by Microsoft, and is not used by MediaCom for any other purpose. The cookie is deleted when a user closes their web browser.Visit the Microsoft site: https://support.microsoft.com/en-gb/kb/899918  
|  **Social media/** **Social Sharing**|   These are cookies that help with the Website’s functionality. These are third party cookies and they allow you to share comments, pages, bookmarks and likes and help to provide access to social networking tools easily  
| | Social media widgets used on this Website include LinkedIn, Twitter and YouTube. These social media widgets collect information about your visit to the Website and your use of the social platform services (for example, buttons or likes) on the Website. We do not share information with these social platforms, however please keep in mind the social networks collect the data of your site visit and interaction with the social widget directly.   
 **Facebook**  | | The cookies allow you to share MediaCom content on Facebook. https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/  
 **LinkedIn**      | | These cookies are set by LinkedIn. We use a number of social media tools to enhance visitor interaction on our site. If you already use these platforms their cookies may be set through our website. Data may then be collected by these companies that enables them to serve up adverts on other sites that they think are relevant to your interests. If you do not use such platforms then our site will not place these cookies on your device. Click here to read more about LinkedIn's cookie policy: https://www.linkedin.com/legal/cookie_policy   
 **Twitter**       | | These cookies are set by Twitter. We use a number of social media tools to enhance visitor interaction on our site. If you already use these platforms their cookies may be set through our website. Data may then be collected by these companies that enables them to serve up adverts on other sites that they think are relevant to your interests. If you do not use such platforms then our site will not place these cookies on your device. Click here to read more about Twitter's cookie policy: https://support.twitter.com/articles/20170514-twitters-use-of-cookies-and-similar-technologies   
 **Vimeo**   | | MediaCom contains pages that may embed video content hosted on Vimeo. These videos do not set cookies automatically, but if you play the video then you may have cookies set by YouTube placed on your computer. https://vimeo.com/cookie_policy   
 **YouTube**   | | MediaCom contains pages that embed video content hosted on YouTube These videos do not set cookies automatically, but if you play the video then you may have cookies set by YouTube placed on your computer. http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy   
 **Google Maps**    | | Google set a number of cookies on any page that includes a Google Map. While we have no control over the cookies set by Google, they appear to include a mixture of pieces of information to measure the number and behaviour of Google Maps users. Click here to learn how to reject or delete the Google cookies: http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/  
  
 ** _Collection and use of contact information_**

There are a few instances where we may collect your name and contact details (such as e-mail address, telephone number and postal address). But, we won’t collect this information without consent and never use it in online advertising placement. Examples where you might voluntarily provide your name and contact details include:

 _Responding to requests_ : we keep a record of information, including email address and other contact information, solely for responding to a user’s request. For example:

  * If you voluntarily ask to be added to our newsletter list, we will collect your e-mail address to send you our email newsletter or marketing emails.
  * If you submit information in connection with an employment inquiry.

By entering your contact information as noted above you are consenting to MediaCom using that information to contact you regarding your request. This consent is our legal basis for using the information in this way.

MediaCom may pass you’re the contact information you provide to our subsidiaries and affiliated companies so that they may contact you in connection with the objective of your inquiry for the purposes set out in this policy. Where we pass your contact information to our subsidiary or affiliated companies in another country, we will make sure that they apply the same level of protection to your information as we do.

If at any time you decide to withdraw your consent and like would us to remove you from our marketing e-mails or newsletters, or to unsubscribe from our database, you can contact us using the details provided at the bottom of this Privacy Notice. You must include your name, e-mail address, and clear instructions regarding changes you are requesting. You may also unsubscribe from e-mail newsletters by clicking on the “unsubscribe” link found at the bottom of the e-mail.

MediaCom is a data controller responsible for your personal data (as this term or similar term is defined by applicable law) when you visit our Website or provide us with contact information.

 ** _California_**

Pursuant to Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California can obtain certain information about the types of personal information that companies with whom they have an established business relationship have shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year. To request a list of companies, if any, to which MediaCom has provided personal information for its own marketing purposes, please email us at [DPO@groupm.com](mailto:DPO@groupm.com). Please allow 30 days for a response.

 ** _Your Rights_**

In addition to your right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes, which we detail above, you also have the following rights in relation to your personal data (some of these rights apply only in certain circumstances, and some of them vary according to the legal basis on which we are processing your data):

  * The right to ask whether we’re processing your personal data and, if we are, to find out details of that processing (as well as obtaining a copy of your personal data).
  * The right to ask us to correct any personal data that we hold about you that’s inaccurate or incomplete.
  * The right to ask us to delete personal data that we hold about you.
  * The right to object to how we’re processing your personal data, and to ask us to restrict how we’re processing your personal data.
  * The right to have the personal data that you’ve provided to us provided to you in a structured and commonly-used electronic format. You can also ask us to transfer your personal data directly to another company if that’s feasible.

 ** _Frequently Asked Questions_**

 **Does MediaCom share any information with other vendors or partners?** :

We may provide access to information we collect to our vendors and contractors (also known as third parties) who are performing services on our behalf to enable the uses of your information that we have described above. These vendors are not permitted to use this information for any other purpose. As noted above the Website uses [social media widgets ](https://www.groupm.com/eu-privacy-policy)including, but not limited to, YouTube, Twitter, and LinkedIn so users can easily share information about their visits with “likes” or “shares.” Always review the privacy policy of social media sites as their data collection practices are separate from MediaCom practices. Additionally, we must disclose information when we believe we’re legally obliged to, or in order to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding prohibited activities, such as incidents of hacking, misuse, suspected fraud, or other prohibited activities.

 **Does MediaCom transfer your Personal Data outside the European Union?:** If you provide us with personal data, we may transfer that personal data to our affiliates and subsidiaries or to other third parties, across borders, and from your country or jurisdiction to other countries or jurisdictions around the world to enable us to use that personal data as described above. Our standard practice is to use European Union model clauses for the transfer of data from the EEA & Switzerland to other non-EEA countries.

 **Use of this site by Children and Children’s data:**

We’re sensitive to children's privacy. Our Website is not developed for or directed at children under age 13. We specifically request that children not provide information about themselves through our Website. If you believe your child has provided this kind of information and would like it deleted from our database, you can contact us at [DPO@groupm.com](mailto:DPO@groupm.com). If we become aware we’ve collected information about a child under the age of 13, we’ll delete it.

 **Data retention and storage:**

We will keep your information that we collect on the Website for a reasonable period for the purposes set out above. We follow generally accepted online advertising industry standards to ensure that your personal data disclosed to us is kept secure, accurate and up to date and kept only for so long as is necessary for the purposes for which it is used. These standards include undertaking necessary physical, electronic, and management activities required to protect data integrity, access, and use.

 **Information Security:**

Maintaining the privacy of our users’ information is very important to us which means we take care and pay special attention to our security measures to protect this information from data breaches. We follow industry standards to protect against the unauthorized access to, retention of, and disclosure of information. This includes physical, electronic, and management activities to protect information integrity, access, and use.

 **Linking to other websites/Third party sites:**

A link from our Website to another website does not imply our endorsement of affiliates or websites, and we do not control third party websites to which we link, nor assume responsibility for their content or privacy policies. Once you follow a link to another website, the MediaCom Privacy Notice no longer applies. It’s important to always read the privacy policy of any website you are visiting.

 **Transfer of data upon change of control:**

In the event that another company acquires us, or all or substantially all of the assets of our business, through a consolidation, merger, asset purchase, or other transaction, we reserve the right to transfer all information (including any information you may have provided through the “contact us” page) that is in our possession or under our control to the acquiring party, and that information may be used by the acquiring party in its business.

 **Data Subject Rights of individuals in the EEA and Switzerland:** You have the right to access, update, change, delete, restrict the use of, or obtain a copy of your Personal Data in an easily readable format. In certain circumstances, you may also request that MediaCom transfer your Personal Data to a third party, and the right to object to its use for marketing purposes. If you wish to exercise any of these rights please contact our DPO at [DPO@GroupM.com](mailto:DPO@GroupM.com).

Where our processing of your personal data is based on your consent, you also have the right to withdraw this consent at any time by contacting our DPO at [DPO@GroupM.com](mailto:DPO@GroupM.com). Please note that your withdrawal of consent will not affect the lawfulness of our processing of your personal data prior to withdrawal of consent.

 **Changes to this Privacy Notice:**

Please note that because of the changing nature of privacy laws and regulations, digital technologies, and our business, we may modify this Privacy Notice from time to time. Please review this Privacy Notice periodically to become aware of any changes that may have occurred (we will update the effective date at the top of the page to help you know when changes have been made).

 **If you have any Complaints or wish to contact us:** Please use the details set out below depending on where you are located and we will do our best to address any complaints or worries you may have about how we collect and handle your Personal Data.

If for whatever reason you don’t feel like we have adequately addressed your concerns you can contact the Data Protection Authority in your jurisdiction and make a formal complaint **.**

MediaCom Holdings Limited

MediaCom Holdings Limited, 124 Theobalds Road, London WC1X 8RX – Attn: MediaCom Legal Department

 **Specific Services Practices:**

The following notices explain specific privacy practices with respect to certain services that MediaCom offers that you may use or be involved with.

 **Real World Insights privacy policy: [Coming soon, in the process of being updated.]**
